Go for the ultimate spin.
Spider-Man is a action, science fiction film directed by Sam Raimi.
After being bitten by a genetically altered spider at Oscorp, nerdy but endearing high school student
Peter Parker is endowed with amazing powers to become the superhero known as Spider-Man.
Spider-Man / Peter Parker, played by Tobey Maguire.
Green Goblin / Norman Osborn, played by Willem Dafoe.
Mary Jane Watson, played by Kirsten Dunst.
Harry Osborn, played by James Franco.
Ben Parker, played by Cliff Robertson.
May Parker, played by Rosemary Harris.
Spider-Man is a 2002 American superhero film based on
the Marvel Comics character Spider-Man.
Directed by Sam Raimi from a screenplay by David Koepp, it is the first
installment in Raimi's Spider-Man trilogy (2002–2007).
Produced by Columbia Pictures and Laura Ziskin Productions in association with Marvel Enterprises, it stars
Tobey Maguire, Willem Dafoe, Kirsten Dunst, James Franco, Cliff Robertson, and Rosemary Harris.
The plot follows the timid teenager Peter Parker, who gains superhuman
abilities after being bitten by a genetically engineered spider.
He adopts the masked persona "Spider-Man" and begins to fight crime in New
York City, facing the malevolent Green Goblin in the process.
Development of a live-action Spider-Man film began in 1975, but stalled
for nearly 25 years due to licensing and financial issues.
Columbia Pictures finally licensed the project for a worldwide release in 1999.
Koepp was hired to create a working screenplay, which was eventually
rewritten by Scott Rosenberg and refined by Alvin Sargent.
Various directors were considered before Raimi was hired in 2000.
Filming took place in Los Angeles and New York City from January to June 2001.
Danny Elfman composed the musical score, while Sony
Pictures Imageworks handled the visual effects.
Spider-Man premiered at the Mann Village Theater on April 29, 2002, and was
released in the United States on May 3, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
It was a tremendous commercial success, becoming the first film to reach $100 million in a single
weekend, as well as the most successful film based on a comic book at the time.
With a box office gross of $826 million worldwide against its $139 million budget, it was the highest-grossing
superhero film, the sixth-highest-grossing film overall at the time, and third highest-grossing film of 2002.
It garnered nominations for Best Sound and Best Visual Effects at the
75th Academy Awards, among numerous other accolades.
Spider-Man is credited for redefining the modern
superhero genre and the summer blockbuster.
It was followed by two sequels, both directed by Raimi:
Spider-Man 2 (2004) and Spider-Man 3 (2007).
Maguire and Dafoe later reprised their roles in Spider-Man: No Way Home (2021), which explores the
concept of the multiverse and links the Raimi trilogy to the Marvel Cinematic Universe.
The film explores themes of new york city, adolescence,
photographer, loss of loved one, photography.
The tone is thought_provoking.